<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Wisdom | littlebigtomatoes]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/blog/categories/wisdom/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-07-20T09:35:05+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krisztian Gyuris]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meeting Heuristics]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/2018/07/meeting-heuristics/"/>
    <updated>2018-07-20T09:19:26+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/2018/07/meeting-heuristics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a collection of heuristics for decinding on meetings. Found it via twitter from <a href="https://fs.blog/about/">Shane Parrish</a>. I subscribed to both of his <a href="https://fs.blog/blog/">blog</a> and twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/farnamstreet">@farnamstreet</a>. He is putting out incredible content on everyday wisdom.</p>

<p>Filling this for myself for future meetings:</p>

<ol>
<li>If you wouldn’t do it right now, say no.</li>
<li>Say no to everything outside of work hours you wouldn’t call your partner and bail on dinner for.</li>
<li>Say no to all recurring meetings with the exception of ones from your boss if you have one. Tell people you’ll opt-in on a per-agenda basis.</li>
<li>Cut all meetings in &frac12;</li>
<li>If you’re in a meeting and it’s clearly pointless, politely excuse yourself.</li>
<li>Keep an internal calculation of what your time is worth. Raise this every year.</li>
<li>If you&rsquo;re going for the drink, don&rsquo;t go.</li>
<li>If you&rsquo;re the smartest person in the room, you&rsquo;re in the wrong meeting.</li>
<li>Even if you can&rsquo;t get out of a meeting, rather than sit there an be bored or make a grocery list, become a detective and see what you can learn from/about everyone else in the meeting.</li>
<li>If everyone is on their phone or laptop at the meeting, leave. The decision has already been made.</li>
<li>If you&rsquo;re talking to signal how smart you are just shut up.</li>
<li>If you&rsquo;re going to &ldquo;add value&rdquo; to someone else&rsquo;s idea, just skip the meeting. That type of stuff is best-done one-on-one and not in a group setting where you reduce the motivation of the other person. (See signally how smart you are (11) and shut up.)</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
