<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Microsoft | littlebigtomatoes]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/blog/categories/microsoft/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-09-30T10:20:43+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krisztian Gyuris]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OverConsumerizing]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/2013/03/overconsumerizing/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-07T08:11:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/2013/03/overconsumerizing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft has the tendency to overdo things. It happened before with .NET around the 2000s. They started to call all of their product ending with .NET. Do you remember Windows Server.NET or Windows CE.NET? Now, they are back with overdoing other stuff such as secrecy, not listening and neglectic developers with Windows Phone and Windows 8. <a href="http://hal2020.com">Hal</a> nails it again:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Let me contrast three strategic thrusts going on at Microsoft.  Windows, Windows Phone, and Azure.  Windows and Windows Phone are in the “shut up and ship” camp.  Azure is in the ENGAGE camp.  It seems like every week Scott Guthrie is announcing new Azure technology previews or releases.  Everything about Azure is exciting.  Amazon, Salesforce, and a few others defined cloud computing.  Azure is displacing them.  It has the Big Mo.  Let me make this clear, AZURE IS GOING TO WIN the cloud computing infrastructure and platform battle.  Meanwhile Windows and Windows Phone continue to alienate their ecosystems.  It is unclear if Windows Phone will ever amount to a significant third ecosystem.  It is unclear that Windows will be able to halt an overall market share decline against IOS and Android tablets.  Azure developers are excited.  No, it’s beyond excitement.  Windows and Windows Phone developers?  Not so much.  They are, at best, conflicted.  Azure is doing platforms right.  Windows and Windows Phone?  They prefer to “shut up and ship”, even if it risks no one caring what they ship&hellip;. <br/></p><footer><strong>hal2020 <a href="http://hal2020.com/2013/03/05/now-i-get-it-the-consumer-guys-at-microsoft-are-just-plain-wrong/">http://hal2020.com/2013/03/05/now-i-get-it-the-consumer-guys-at-microsoft-are-just-plain-wrong/</a> Now I get it</strong> <cite>The Consumer Guys at Microsoft Are Just Plain Wrong!</cite></footer></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Will Windows Phone 8 and Lumia Come Around Finally?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/2012/12/will-windows-phone-8-and-lumia-come-around-finally/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-11T16:42:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/2012/12/will-windows-phone-8-and-lumia-come-around-finally</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>Microsoft and Nokia&rsquo;s marketing blitz is really paying off. Over Thanksgiving weekend, there were several instances where regular people off the street commented or approached me about the phone. The first time was at a diner in Union Square. The waitress recognized the phone and asked to take it to the back to show her co-worker who is obsessed with Windows 8.</p></p><p><p>Then, on Thanksgiving itself &ndash; as I was taking photos of my food (the Warren-Robertson household is not traditional, as we go out to eat on Thanksgiving) &ndash; other patrons in the restaurant recognized the Lumia and there were points and stares and murmurs about the device.</p></p><p><p>I never expected that. At all.</p><footer><strong>Mashable <a href="http://mashable.com/2012/11/27/living-with-lumia-wrap-up/">http://mashable.com/2012/11/27/living-with-lumia-wrap-up/</a> Living With Lumia: The Final Verdict on Windows Phone 8</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>There is something in the air!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
