<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Android | littlebigtomatoes]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/blog/categories/android/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-07-20T08:20:47+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krisztian Gyuris]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Disabling Captive Portal Check in Android]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/2017/02/disabling-captive-portal-check-in-android/"/>
    <updated>2017-02-11T19:44:15+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/2017/02/disabling-captive-portal-check-in-android</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently had an issue with an Android phone that kept disconnecting from the wifi network after a certain period.
The wifi was configured to do a captive portal style authentication check, showing me a webpage after connection that asked me to authenticate myself in order to use the network.
When not authenticating for a certain period of time the Android phone disconnected from the wireless network causing me to wonder what is happening.</p>

<p>It seems that this is the default behavior of Android and this is how you can disable this behavior:</p>

<ul>
<li> First download and install <strong>adb</strong> on your machine.
 <a href="https://developer.android.com/studio/releases/platform-tools.html">SDK Platform Tools from Google</a></li>
<li> Extract the download and navigate the the folder where the adb executable located.</li>
<li> Connect your Android phone to your machine with the USB cable</li>
<li> Then launch the adb shell<br/>
<code>bash   
adb shell
</code></li>
<li> Type the following command to turn off captive portal check
<code>bash   
settings put global captive_portal_detection_enabled 0
</code></li>
<li> Type to see if the value of the configuration key is 0
<code>bash   
settings get global captive_portal_detection_enabled
</code></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Android Catching Up to iOS?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/2013/01/is-android-catching-up-to-ios/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-18T08:32:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/2013/01/is-android-catching-up-to-ios</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>And believe me or not, but after having configured my Nexus 4 just the way I always wanted – providing me with the fastest access to my most frequently used apps along with the most important information on a single screen – whenever I grab my iPhone for testing purposes, iOS feels pretty old, outdated and less user friendly. For me, there currently is no way of going back. Once you get used to all of these capabilities, it’s hard to live without them.</p><footer><strong>Ralf Rottmann - <a href="http://www.24100.net/2013/01/an-iphone-lovers-confession-i-switched-to-the-nexus-4-completely/">http://www.24100.net/2013/01/an-iphone-lovers-confession-i-switched-to-the-nexus-4-completely/</a> An iPhone lover&rsquo;s confession: I switched to the Nexus 4. Completely.</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>I left the Android platform as a user about a year ago and I left with bad memories. This is an excellent write up about the current state of Android and made me want to go back and experience it once more. It also seems that the correct way to experience android via the reference devices made by Google.</p>

<p>And <a href="http://mycolorscreen.com/popular/">those screens</a> are just gorgeous!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
