<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Recipes | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://gyurisc.github.io/blog/categories/recipes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gyurisc.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-22T13:54:40+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://gyurisc.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krisztian Gyuris]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reverse Todo Process]]></title>
    <link href="http://gyurisc.github.io/2012/12/reverse-todo-process/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-31T08:52:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://gyurisc.github.io/2012/12/reverse-todo-process</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my <a href="http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/2012/12/todo-or-todont/">previous article</a>, I wrote about the my motivations using the Anti Todo list and how it took out tons of stress of my daily life. This way of doing things works well for me and here is how I implemented it.</p>

<!--more-->


<p></p>

<p><img src="/images/20121218_anti_todo.png" title="&lsquo;Anti Todo&rsquo; &lsquo;Anti Todo list in Sublime Text 2&rsquo;" ></p>

<p>The idea here is to have this list everywhere and to be easily accessible and synchronized all the time. For synchronization I am using the <a href="http://www.dropbox.com">Dropbox</a> service. In the root of my dropbox folder I created a file called anti.todo The easiest way of do something like this from your bash command line:</p>

<pre><code>touch anti.todo 
</code></pre>

<p>With this, the synchronization part of my solution is taken care of. For creation of the items you will need to have Sublime Text 2 installed on your machine, which is a terrific text editor. You will need the <a href="https://github.com/aziz/PlainTasks">PlainTasks</a> package to be installed as well. This package will be responsible for displaying the list. You can learn how to use the <a href="http://youtu.be/VQMU0PDfXyA">PlainTasks</a> package.</p>

<p>Once it is all set, you can open the anti.todo file with Sublime Text 2 and start adding your achivements to the list like this:</p>

<ul>
<li>Add todays date with a colon at the end. Underneath, you will collect the list you achieved for today.</li>
<li>If you have done something then press ⌘+enter (ctrl+enter on Windows) to add achievement for today.</li>
<li>After adding the new achievement, press ⌘+D (ctrl+d on Windows) to mark your achievement as done</li>
<li>Also you can use tags using @ sign, like this @tag</li>
<li>Once you are done for today just save the file.</li>
<li>Rinse and repeat.</li>
</ul>


<p>Another alternative I can recommend on thhe Mac for creating this list is <a href="http://www.hogbaysoftware.com/products/taskpaper">TaskPaper</a> for the Mac, or try <a href="http://widefido.com/products/todopaper/">TodoPaper</a> on Windows.</p>

<p>If you find this usefull and start using yourself, please let me know how it works out for you!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Developer Recipes - Using Git and Dropbox Together]]></title>
    <link href="http://gyurisc.github.io/2012/05/developer-recipes-using-git-and-dropbox-together/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-07T16:13:28+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://gyurisc.github.io/2012/05/developer-recipes-using-git-and-dropbox-together</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love coding. My work is my hobby and I like to write small little apps and tools that I can use myself. I also use several machines with multiple operating systems on them and I need a workflow that would allow me to seamlesly synchornize between my machines. For this I created this process that involves git and dropbox, to keep my personal projects under source code control and have it synchroned to all my machines automatically. So I decided to document this method here.</p>

<!--more-->


<p></p>

<p><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> I do not invented this method. Originally I saw the idea on stackoverflow.com:</p>

<p><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1960799/using-gitdropbox-together-effectively">Stackoverflow - Using git dropbox together effectively?</a></p>

<p>I am also not convinced that this method is suitable for more than one person to use. I am a single developer and this process fits my need perfectly.</p>

<h3>Overview</h3>

<p>I use Visual Studio.NET 2010, <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/">dropbox</a> and <a href="http://code.google.com/p/msysgit/">msysgit</a> on all my Windows machines. I am mainly developing for my Windows Phone and soon I will try to create Metro Apps for Windows 8. Although, this will be .NET and Visual Studio centric recipe, you can still use it with your own stuff. The only crucial component is dropbox and git.</p>

<p>Let say, you have two machines. One laptop that you carry around and one desktop. Both have dropbox and git installed. You start creating your project on your laptop, but when you arrive home you would like to continue the coding on your desktop machine. So what will happen is the following:</p>

<ul>
<li>I will set up the project on my laptop and add it to the git source control</li>
<li>I will initialize a bare repository on my laptop’s dropbox folder.</li>
<li>Will push the project to dropbox.</li>
<li>Get the project on the desktop machine</li>
</ul>


<h3>Setting up project and add it to git</h3>

<ul>
<li>Set up your Visual Studio.NET project and do some coding</li>
</ul>


<p>First, thing first is to create your application in Visual Studio.NET 2010. I will create a new todo app for my Windows Phone called <strong>TodoApp_WP7</strong>. Cannot see enough todo app on this new platform yet. So we need one :)</p>

<ul>
<li>Initialize the git repository in the solution folder</li>
</ul>


<p>Open up msysgit and navigate to your solution folder. Initialize your git repo and your
<code>
git init
</code>
Before adding your project files, it is a good idea to create a .gitognore file. Here you can specify what files you want to exclude from source code controll! So in your msysgit command line you issue this command to create .gitignore and add the things you would like to ignore.</p>

<pre><code>touch .gitignore
notepad .gitignore
</code></pre>

<p>I have something like this in my .gitignore</p>

<pre><code>User-specific files

*.suo
*.user
*.sln.docstates

Others

[Bb]in
[Oo]bj
</code></pre>

<p>Then you can add your files and do your first commit</p>

<pre><code>git add .
git commit -m “first commit”
</code></pre>

<h3>Pushing the changes to Dropbox</h3>

<ul>
<li>Create a git folder in your Dropbox folder and initialize a bare git repository</li>
</ul>


<p>Navigate to your git dropbox folder and create your bare repository. Navigating in the git shell can be tricky to someone, who knows only windows command line.</p>

<p>My Dropbox is installed on my machine here D:\Dropbox, so to go to that folder you need to issue this command:
<code>
cd /d/Dropbox/git
git init —bare TodoApp_WP7.git
</code>
  * Adding remotes</p>

<p>Now you need to go back to your project directory and configure the dropbox folder as the origin for your project. I also add a remote called dropbox as a convenience.
<code>
git remote add origin /d/Dropbox/git/TodoApp_WP7.git
git remote add dropbox /d/Dropbox/git/TodoApp_WP7.git
</code>
 * Push the project to your bare dropbox repository</p>

<p>Now you need to push the project to your dropbox repository
<code>
 git push -u origin master
</code>
  * On your other machine just simply do a git clone to get the project</p>

<h3>Getting your project from Dropbox to another computer for the first time</h3>

<p>When logging on to your other machine you will see that dropbox is busy to refresh all the files you were changing or it already has been happened. All you need to do is to open up the git client on your machine, navigate to your dev folder an issue the command
<code>
git clone /d/Dropbox/git/TodoApp_WP7.git
</code></p>

<p>This will create the folder in your dev folder and gets the source code of your app. You will need not to worry about remotes, however you can create anew remote called dropbox, if you like.
Now you are ready to launch Visual Studio on the machine and do some changes. After finishing your work you can return to the git command line and issue the following command to find out what has changed:
<code>
git status
</code></p>

<p>You will see all files that are changed or new. You will need to add the changes to your change set and commit these changes .</p>

<pre><code>git add .
git commit -m “My new changes to my app”
</code></pre>

<p>With the commit command you added all the changes to your git repository. However, you still need to push these changes to your dropbox. It is called origin and it is automatically created when you cloned your project from dropbox.</p>

<p>All you need to do is to issue the following command:</p>

<pre><code>git push
</code></pre>

<p>Now you are done with all the changes and these are now synchronized on all your developer machines.</p>

<h3>Getting the changes for your project on a machine that already has your project.</h3>

<p>This is the simples command. All you need to do is to go to your project repository and do a pull operation:</p>

<pre><code>git pull
</code></pre>

<p>I hope that you will find this method useful for synchronizing code between your computer via dropbox and git. If you have any questions, please do not hesitate to contact me!</p>

<h3>Useful links</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/AlexZeitler/gitcheatsheet/blob/master/gitcheatsheet.pdf">git cheat sheet</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
