<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Emailme | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://gyurisc.github.io/blog/categories/emailme/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gyurisc.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-22T13:57:42+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://gyurisc.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krisztian Gyuris]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[EmailMe for Windows Phone 7]]></title>
    <link href="http://gyurisc.github.io/2012/11/emailme-for-windows-phone-7/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-27T08:53:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://gyurisc.github.io/2012/11/emailme-for-windows-phone-7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This post was written by me about two months ago, then I forgot about it. I decided to publish it regardless. This app did not really live up to the plans downloadwise, but I am still happy with it. I plan to write a follow up and discuss what I learnt from it marketing and business wise!</em></p>

<p>In the last three-four months I worked on my first app called <a href="http://hotbidd.com/apps/wp7/emailme/">EmailMe</a>, while commuting and now it is available on the marketplace for 0.99.</p>

<!--more-->


<ul>
<li>Download <a href="http://hotbidd.com/apps/wp7/emailme/">EmailMe</a> from the <a href="http://www.windowsphone.com/en-us/store/app/emailme/109144f2-8629-42fd-99d9-9e0ce7ec1cc1">Marketplace</a></li>
</ul>


<p>With this app I had two goals. I wanted to make something that would fit my need and would use daily and I wanted to make something really polished
and nice looking. I think I achieved both of these goals. I like how the app looks and I use it every day several time.</p>

<p>EmailMe is a simple app that let&rsquo;s you to create messages and send them to yourself.</p>

<p>Why would anyone send messages to themselves? Isn&rsquo;t it just a littlebit weird? Let me explain.</p>

<p>I switched from Android app about a year ago when I received my belowed Lumia 800. On the Android phone I had several apps I relied on like the Kindle app, Audible or Google Listen. I had a Kindle client on Windows Phone 7 on day one and the phone is very great doing pdocast. Audible app now is finally available as well.</p>

<p>I also was a big user of the EEBA can help website. It is a finanacial website that let&rsquo;s you to implement a budget system and enter your spendings. It has a great iPhone and Android client that syncs flawlesly with the website. When, I contacted them and asked them if there is a cleint for Windows Phone 7 they politely told me that they do not have one and not planning to create one in the near future.</p>

<p>So I started to send email messages to myself to record what I spent money on the day nad entered these records at the evening into the EEBA site. Creating 5-10 meail messages on the phone was kind of repeptitve and clumsy. Over and over I had to enter the first few letters of my email. Provide a subject line and hit send button.</p>

<p>So I envisioned an app that would be helping me to send email where I do not need to enter email addresses over and over and I do not need to fill the subject line.</p>

<p>The app would fast to start, I would type in my message and hit send. No more worries about addresses and subject lines. The message would act as the subject line - truncated over certain length - and the message as well.</p>

<p>I put together a quick and dirty prototype and started using it. While using, I ironed out the bugs and starting to add features that I have missed.</p>

<p>Since then I gave up EEBA and switched to use YNAB which is awesome! Unfortunately no client for the wp7 platform yet. But I use my app everyday to post my spending records and notes. This workflow where I use my inbox as container for action items works for me very well as I clean out my inbox every day. Spending records are going to YNAB and notes or todos are going to todo application.</p>

<p>I also spent lot of time to polish the app. I added handling multiple email addresses. History for previous messages. I made sure that the app looks nice, bright and clean. The text is well readable even to me! :)</p>

<p>I also added a feature where I can learn how much I used the phone. How much messages I sent and the total time! The feature did not make too much sense, but I enjoyed implementing it.</p>

<p>All in all it was very enjoyable and fun time to implement the app and I learned a lot about the technology! It was a nice first step&hellip; now on to the next app!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
