<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Keyboard Shortcuts | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://gyurisc.github.io/blog/categories/keyboard-shortcuts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://gyurisc.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-27T16:55:58+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://gyurisc.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Krisztian Gyuris]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keyboard Shortcuts for Windows 8]]></title>
    <link href="http://gyurisc.github.io/2012/12/keyboard-shortcuts-for-windows-8/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T07:54:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://gyurisc.github.io/2012/12/keyboard-shortcuts-for-windows-8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I released my first app for Windows 8! Now you can download <a href="http://apps.microsoft.com/windows/en-US/app/keyboard-shortcuts/a098e87b-cbeb-49ad-a356-c19b4c025afb">Keyboard Shortcuts App</a> from the Windows Store for Free.</p>

<p>As you might guessed, I am quite a bit of fan of productivity and doing things fast and swift on my computers. One of the main driver of productivity on a desktop computer are keyboard shortcuts. With Windows 8, it is even more so! I believe <a href="http://www.littlebigtomatoes.com/2012/12/keyboard-shortcut-starter-kit-for-windows-8/">keyboard shortcuts</a> on Windows 8 are essential to be productive.</p>

<!--more-->


<p></p>

<p>To help myself and hopefully others to memorize these shortcuts I created an app that makes easy to find and learn the shortcuts. Currently, it contains about 100 shortcuts for Windows 8, Calendar and Mail. I am hoping to add more shortcuts and other applications soon.</p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/HiyMIWcum_c "></iframe></div></p>

<p>If you have any feedback, issues or you think there is something missing just ping me on twitter. I would be happy to help you!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keyboard Shortcut Starter Kit for Windows 8]]></title>
    <link href="http://gyurisc.github.io/2012/12/keyboard-shortcut-starter-kit-for-windows-8/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-04T08:58:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://gyurisc.github.io/2012/12/keyboard-shortcut-starter-kit-for-windows-8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As you might found out I am huge fan of Microsoft&rsquo;s latest operating system Windows 8. I love the new Start Screen and how fast the metro style apps are. I am waiting for a touch based device that runs Windows 8, but until I have a touch device at hand and can try all the touch features, I am stuck with a standard pre-touch laptop.</p>

<p>Windows 8 is also very nice on a standard PC and what really makes it fly high are the keyboard shortcuts. I highly encourage you to try those and memorize them. Once they become muscle memory, they will make you super-fast and productive.</p>

<!--more-->


<p></p>

<p>I would like to present you with a collection of the most useful and essential shortcuts:</p>

<p><strong>Windows</strong> key is the mother of all shortcuts on Windows 8. It will get you to the Start Screen from the current app and back to your previous app, if you press it once more. Once you are on the Start Screen, just start typing and it will search the apps that you have installed. This is the fastest way to start the apps on your system.</p>

<p><strong>Windows + D</strong>, gets you to the classic desktop and back to the app you were using, if you press it once more.
The next shortcut is <em>Windows + C</em>, that brings up the charms bar. This one lets you access the charms such as search or settings. It will also show the current date and time, the battery and network status on the bottom left side of the screen.</p>

<p><strong>Windows + I</strong> is the shortcut I use the most. This brings up the settings charm and you can switch on and off the airport mode, audio volume and brightness and control panel directly. As a laptop user, I find it very convenient to be able to switch Wi-Fi on/off with two clicks.</p>

<p><strong>Windows + Space</strong> is my all-time favorite. This one lets you to change the input language or cycle them through if you press it many times. The reason while I am so enthusiastic about this one is because I am using its twin sister on OS X <em>Apple + Space</em> to switch input language. For me this is a welcome change, because in the past I often found myself trying the shortcut, when using Windows 7 just to find out that this is a different OS and this will be not working here. This is not the case anymore and I can rely on muscle memory to switch the input language. I am truly happy!</p>

<p><strong>Windows + X</strong> is the last one. This keyboard shortcut is for the power users. It will bring up an advanced menu on the bottom left side of the screen and there will be menus to access all the advanced features of the operating system such Command Prompt Admin, Task Manager, Control Panel, File Explorer. This comes very handy, if you need to access the more advanced functions a lot.</p>

<p>This is my start kit of keyboard shortcuts for Windows8. I hope it will help you to become faster. Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crossing the Rubicon]]></title>
    <link href="http://gyurisc.github.io/2012/11/crossing-the-rubicon/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T10:11:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://gyurisc.github.io/2012/11/crossing-the-rubicon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Once in every few years I have this moment, when I start to use something new and I realize that this thing will stay with me and I cannot go back anymore to the old stuff!</p>

<p>Couple of days ago I had this moment with Windows 8, because of a keyboard shortcut!</p>

<!--more-->


<p></p>

<p>I clearly remember when I first installed Google Chrome and realized that is far superior to the browser that I was using before Chrome. The moment for me when I realized that I will not be able to switch back to IE was when I discovered that I can create shortcuts out of websites such as Gmail and when launching Chrome it will present the site for me as an app!</p>

<p>Before that I had such moment, when I discovered Gmail and the way Gmail is using labels instead of folders. I instantly said goodbye to Outlook and Hotmail and Yahoo Mail! Whenever I had to use Outlook at work it was such a pain afterwards and I just could not understand why I was putting up with this slow beast for so long!</p>

<p>Years before that I discovered IE4 is much superior to Netscape and I do not remember what was the tiny feature that pushed me over to use IE, but I never turned back!</p>

<p>The Kindle ditched the PDF. iPod with iTunes decimated Windows Media based no-name portable player in my life. Because of Instapaper I stopped using RSS readers.</p>

<p>They all had tiny features that pushed me over and made me never look back. Kindle had seamless syncing. Instapaper allowed me to read longer articles in a clutter free format. iPod and iTunes were far superior, but the final straw for me were the seamless podcast experience!</p>

<p>I started to use Windows 8 as my full time operating system since the consumer preview. I generally liked this newest operating system and its new start screen, but what pushed me over finally was a keyboard shortcut.</p>

<p><strong>Windows + Spacebar</strong></p>

<p>This shortcut is for switching input language in Windows. OS X had the Apple Key and Spacebar shortcut since I started to use Macs and it was one of my favorite shortcut on that platform.</p>

<p>When I discovered this keyboard shortcut to switch languages and started using it on Windows 8, I found myself more and more annoyed when I needed to switch from English to Hungarian on my Windows 7 desktop at work. That one click on the language not tolerable anymore.</p>

<p>Since that moment I found more and more new stuff to like in Windows 8 every day and less and less I could bear Windows 7. In my eyes, these small moments that make the difference between a great product and a good one!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
